时间索引：
00:20 视频出处
00:30 发射数据
00:45 背景音乐索引
01:54 节目正式开始
16:39 火箭发射倒计时15秒
17:58 火箭超音速&Max-Q
19:15 一级发动机关机&一二级分离&二级点火
20:36 整流罩分离
23:09 一级再入点火
24:26 一级着陆点火
27:05 二级发动机关机
31:07 SAOCOM-1B分离
01:18:35 Tyvak-0172，GNOMES-1分离
[Music]
[音乐]
原作者名：SpaceX
视频来源：youtu.be/-P-gLOsDjE3E
原视频发布日期：20200830
字幕翻译/压制：旋火
参考：猎鹰9号发射呼号：reddit.com/r/SpaceXLounge/comments/6jjpxk/spacex_callouts/，news.ycombinator.com/item?id=9377014
SAOCOM-1B任务控制音频：youtu.be/9mED5Dt0GhU
发射数据
国家：美国
时间：2020/8/30 23:18:56(UTC)
位置：Cape Canaveral SLC-40
(卡纳维拉尔角空军基地40号发射复合体)
提供商：SpaceX
客户：CONAE(阿根廷航天局)，
Tyvak，PlanetIQ
有效载荷：SAOCOM 1B，
Tyvak-0172，GNOMES-1
有效载荷质量：3.13吨
载具：猎鹰9号Block 5(B1059.4)
轨道：600km SSO(太阳同步轨道)
结果：成功
备注：1969年以来卡角第一次发射SSO载荷，
于LZ-1陆地着陆场返场回收成功，
SpaceX第100次发射
数据来源：英文维基
航天爱好者网(www.spaceflightfans.cn/event/
falcon-9-saocom-1b-capella-2-gnomes-1)
素材出处：Starlink Mission-SpaceX-
20200830-youtu.be/P-gLOsDjE3E
背景音乐索引：00:02 Crew by Test Shot Starfish
27:40 Cities In Flight by Test Shot Starfish
32:07 FlyBy by Test Shot Starfish
38:06 In The Shadow Of Giants by Test Shot Starfish
44:03 Resonator by Test Shot Starfish
49:20 Trouble by Test Shot Starfish
55:25 Re - Flight by Test Shot Starfish
01:00:52 Approaching Dragon by Test Shot Starfish
01:07:36 Andromeda by Test Shot Starfish
01:12:46 Rollout by Test Shot Starfish
01:20:51 Crew by Test Shot Starfish
太空发射综合体40
地球，佛罗里达，
卡纳维拉尔角，SLC-40
二级煤油加注
二级液氧加注
Good evening. It's Sunday August 30th.
晚上好 今天是8月30日星期天
And we're here at SpaceX headquarters in Hawthorne California.
我们现在在加州霍桑的SpaceX总部
You're looking at a live view of the Falcon 9 rocket
你现在看到的是猎鹰9号火箭的实时画面
as it awaits at 7:18 pm eastern time launch
它正等待着在美国东部时间(夏令时UTC-4)19:18分
from Cape Canaveral Air Force Station in Florida.
从佛罗里达州卡纳维拉尔角空军基地发射
My name is Michael Andrews
我是Michael Andrews
and I'm a supply chain supervisor here at SpaceX.
我是SpaceX的供应链主管
For tonight's mission
关于今晚的任务
we'll be placing the SAOCOM 1B Earth observation satellite into a low-Earth sun-synchronous orbit
我们将把SAOCOM 1B地球观测卫星送入近地太阳同步轨道
for the National Commission of Space Activities of Argentina known as CONAE.
这是阿根廷国家空间活动委员会(CONAE)的卫星
Now it's the second and final satellite of our SAOCOM constellation.
那么 它是SAOCOM星座的第二颗也是最后一颗卫星
If you recall SpaceX launched the first satellite SAOCOM 1A
如果大家还记得SpaceX发射了该星座的第一颗卫星 SAOCOM 1A
back in october 2018 from vandenberg Air Force base in Florida.
Florida是主持人口胡
那时是在2018年10月在加州范登堡空军基地进行的发射
The satellite's main goal is to gather soil moisture information.
该卫星的主要目的是收集土壤水分信息
The data provided by SAOCOM helps increase productivity and competitiveness of sectors like agriculture.
SAOCOM提供的数据有助于提高农业等部门的生产力和竞争力
By generating for example risk maps that can help control crop diseases.
例如通过生成风险地图 可以帮助控制作物疾病
By implementing efficient fertilizer systems and for early flood warnings.
还能实现高效的施肥系统 以及进行洪水预警
The two SAOCOM satellites will work in partnership with Italy's COSMO-SkyMed constellation.
SAOCOM的两颗卫星将与意大利的COSMO-SkyMed星座合作
All the satellites will work together to provide Earth imaging.
所有卫星将共同提供地球成像
Each SAOCOM satellite can acquire about 225 images every day.
每颗SAOCOM卫星每天可获取约225幅图像
We also have two smaller ride share satellites on board.
我们还有两颗较小的拼车卫星
Tyvak-0172 and the GNOMES-1 small sat for PlanetIQ.
Tyvak-0172和PlanetIQ的GNOMES-1小卫星
Now PlanetIQ designs, builds, launches and operates
那么 PlanetIQ公司设计 建造 发射和运营
one of the most advanced constellations of radio occultation weather forecasting satellites.
最先进的无线电掩星气象预报卫星星座之一
Radio occultation is a technology that measures and analyzes the signals generated by GPS satellites
无线电掩星是一种测量和分析GPS卫星产生的信号的技术
to determine weather data such as pressure temperature and water vapor.
通过这种技术 来确定压力 温度和水汽等天气数据
This data is used in weather forecast models to greatly improve the accuracy
这些数据被用于天气预报模型中 大大提高了天气预报的准确性
and extend the range of those weather predictions.
并扩大这些天气预报的范围
Now tonight's launch is an especially exciting one.
今晚的发射比较特别 令人振奋
It's SpaceX's first polar orbit from the East Coast.
这是SpaceX首次在美国东海岸发射极地轨道卫星
A polar orbit is one in which satellites pass above the north and south poles as opposed to the equator.
极地轨道是指卫星经过南北两极上方 而不是赤道
This is the first polar trajectory since the late 1960s fallen out of Cape Canaveral.
这是自20世纪60年代末 第一次从卡纳维拉尔角进行极地轨道发射
SpaceX worked closely with the Air Force and the FAA to create a trajectory
SpaceX与美国空军和联邦航空管理局密切合作研究出一种弹道
that meets the necessary safety requirements for flight.
以符合必要的发射安全要求
Falcon 9's autonomous flight termination system.
猎鹰9号的自主飞行终止系统
Its exceptional reliability and its improved performance over heritage launch vehicles
其卓越的可靠性 还有比传统运载火箭更好的性能
is a key factor in why SpaceX is able to meet the unique performance and safety challenges
是SpaceX能够满足安全要求下的独特性能的关键因素
of launching this polar mission safely from the Cape
使这次从卡角安全进行极轨道发射成为了可能
while still delivering the payload to its desired orbit.
同时还能将有效载荷送入目标轨道
Due to the flight path tonight, people along the eastern coast of Florida including Miami
由于今晚的发射弹道 包括迈阿密在内的佛罗里达州东海岸地区的人们
may be able to see Falcon 9 as it launches the space
可能会看到猎鹰9号发射到太空时的景象
as well as our second stage burn following stage separation
这包括一二级分离后的二级点火
and maybe even the first stage boosts back burn as it makes its way back to Earth for landing.
甚至可能看到一级火箭在返回地球着陆时的返场点火
And because of the time of the day of launch about 30 minutes before sunset
而由于发射当天的时间是在日落前30分钟左右
we might get nice illuminations of the contrails if clouds aren't in the way.
如果没有云层的阻挡 我们可能会看到很好的尾迹夜光云
Now let's take a look at Falcon 9 out on the pad of the Cape.
现在让我们来看看猎鹰9号在卡角发射台上的情况
Good evening my name is Andy Tran and I'm a production supervisor here at SpaceX.
晚上好 我是Andy Tran 我是SpaceX的生产主管
We're looking at a live view of Falcon 9.
我们现在看到的是猎鹰9号的实时画面
Our 70-meter two-stage liquid fuel launch vehicle as it sits at Cape Canaveral.
我们的70米两级液体燃料运载火箭正坐落在卡纳维拉尔角
The bottom two-thirds of the vehicle is the first stage.
一级火箭位于运载火箭下部三分之二的位置
Its objective is to accelerate the vehicle through the Earth's atmosphere
它的作用是在穿越地球大气层时加速运载火箭
and then separate from the rest of the rocket.
然后与火箭的其他部分分离
For today's mission it's going to be the fourth flight for this particular first stage booster.
今天的任务将是这枚助推器(一级火箭)的第四次飞行
It previously supported two cargo resupply missions, CRS 19 and 20
它曾进行过两次货物补给任务 CRS 19和CRS 20
as well as our ninth Starlink launch in June of this year.
以及我们在今年6月的第九次星链发射
Like its previous missions we are going to be attempting to recover this booster
和以前的任务一样 我们将尝试回收这枚助推器
but this time back at land on landing zone one.
但这次会使用陆地上的一号着陆区进行回收
Now after the first stage separates,
那么在一级火箭分离后
the second stage will then carry the SAOCOM 1B and our two rideshare satellites to a Sun Synchronous Orbit.
二级将携带SAOCOM 1B和我们的两颗拼车卫星进入太阳同步轨道
Sun Synchronous Orbits travel over the Earth's poles as the planet rotates underneath
太阳同步轨道在地球的两极上空运行 而地球在其下方旋转
with the satellite passing over a particular section of the Earth at the same time each day.
在这个轨道上的卫星每天在同一时间经过地球的某一特定区域
This type of orbit also provides a constant amount of sunlight
这种类型的轨道还提供了持续的太阳光
making them especially good for imaging satellites like the ones we have on board tonight.
使得它们特别适合于成像卫星 就像我们今晚搭载的那些卫星一样
At the top of the rocket you'll notice a large nose cone.
在火箭的顶部 你会注意到一个大鼻锥
This is called the satellite fairing.
这就是卫星整流罩
It's a composite structure
(猎鹰9号的整流罩)是一种复合材料结构
and protects the rocket from the forces of ascent and also houses our payloads.
保护火箭免受上升段气动力的影响 同时放置有效载荷
Once the vehicle is outside of the Earth's atmosphere, the fairing will separate to expose the satellites into space.
一旦飞行器离开地球大气层 整流罩就会分离 将卫星暴露在太空中
For tonight's mission both fairing halves are brand new.
今晚的任务中 两瓣(半)儿整流罩都是全新的
We only have one recovery ship supporting today's mission.
我们只有一艘回收船支持今天的任务
Ms. Chief you can see on screen right now
也就是你现在在屏幕上看到的首席女士号
so we won't be able to attempt to catch these fairing halves
所以我们就不能试图同时抓住这两瓣整流罩了
but rather try to scoop them out of the water once they land.
不过还是会尝试在它们降落后将他们从水中擓(kuǎi)出来
The other recovery vessel, Ms. Tree was positioned to support today's Starlink mission
另一艘回收船树女士号的之前处在支援今天星链任务(V1.0-L11)的位置
which has now been rescheduled for later on this week.
现在星链任务已经改期为本周晚些时候
and finally the large truss structure next to Falcon 9 is called the Transporter Erector or TE.
最后 猎鹰9号旁边的大型桁架结构被称为火箭运输起竖机或TE
The te's job is to roll Falcon 9 out to the launch pad, raise it to a vertical launch position
TE的工作是将猎鹰9号运到发射台 并将其抬起到垂直发射位置
and also route power, fluids and communication to the rocket and satellite.
并将电力 液体和通信输送到火箭和卫星上
Falcon 9 rolled out to the pad with the payload on Friday evening
在周五晚上 猎鹰9号带着有效载荷运往发射台
and went vertical yesterday at 2pm eastern local time.
并于当地时间昨天14点起竖
The SpaceX chief engineer held a technical poll at T-minus one hour
在发射前1小时 SpaceX首席工程师举行了一次技术性投票
and our launch director held a propellant load and launch go no-go poll at t-minus 38 minutes.
而在38分钟后 我们的发射主管 进行了是否进行推进剂加注和发射的投票
If we do have to call a hold on today's launch for any reason,
如果今天的发射因为任何原因而不得不暂停的话
we do have a backup opportunity tomorrow same time pending range acceptance.
明天同一时间 我们还有一个备用的机会 如果发射区域条件允许的话
In terms of fuel Falcon 9 began loading propellants at T-minus 35 minutes
在燃料方面 猎鹰9号在倒计时35分钟开始加注推进剂
and that process is still currently underway.
而这一过程目前仍在进行中
Falcon 9 uses a refined form of kerosene called RP-1, Rocket Propellant 1 for its fuel
猎鹰9号的燃料为RP-1 是一种精炼煤油 全称1号火箭推进剂
and super chilled liquid oxygen known as LOX for its oxidizer.
而氧化剂为低温液氧(LOX)
Currently RP-1 is nearly fully loaded on the first stage about 36 000 gallons
目前 一级的RP-1几乎加注完成 差不多136.3m³
and the second stage is fully fueled at about 9600 gallons.
而第二级的RP-1已经加满 大约36.3m³
Liquid oxygen though it's still loading on both stages.
不过两个分级上的液氧都还在加注
In terms of helium, we've also begun to load helium into Falcon 9.
在氦气方面 我们也开始在猎鹰9号上加注氦气
The vehicle uses helium gas as a pressurant and helps push the RP-1 and LOX through the Merlin engines.
火箭使用氦气作为增压剂 它能让RP-1和LOX通过梅林发动机
Think of like your car. Gravity keeps all the fuel at the bottom.
就像你的汽车一样 重力使所有的燃料都沉在底部
We don't have that luxury in zero gravity.
但在零重力状态下 没有这种奢侈品
So the helium pushes that fuel to our engine's turbo pumps.
所以氦气会把燃料推到发动机的涡轮泵上 (然后再由涡轮泵完成进一步加压)
And then at T-minus seven minutes our engine chill process will begin.
然后在倒计时7分钟 就会开始发动机的冷却过程
This is where we allow a small amount of the super chilled LOX to flow into the Merlin engine's turbo pumps
这时会让少量的超冷LOX流进梅林发动机的涡轮泵中
prior to the full flow of LOX into the vehicle.
这在火箭(发动机)全面使用LOX之前
This helps us avoid any kind of thermal shocks to the system
这样 系统不会受到热量冲击
that LOX is negative 338 degrees Fahrenheit after all.
毕竟LOX处在零下205.56°C
Finally the Transporter Erector will retract away from the rocket
最后 火箭运输起竖机将从火箭上缩回
slightly at around T-minus four and a half minutes
这差不多发生在倒计时4分半的时候
and this provides enough clearance for Falcon 9 to lift off.
这样 猎鹰9号的升空就有了足够的空间
The vehicle is healthy and the folks in mission control are currently working no issues on the rocket.
现在 火箭状态良好 任务控制部门的人员没发现火箭有问题
In terms of the payload at T-minus 15 minutes, the SAOCOM 1B satellite
就有效载荷而言 倒计时15分钟时 SAOCOM 1B卫星
finished transitioning from external to internal power.
从外部电源切换到了内部电源
Our two rideshare small sats were already on internal power before the countdown began.
在倒计时开始之前 两个搭车小卫星就已经在使用内部电源了
It's been a busy week weekend at the Cape
在卡角 这是一个繁忙的周末
with a lot of launch opportunities but the range is approving us and accepting this launch attempt.
有很多的发射机会 不过现在发射区域条件是允许我们进行发射的
But weather... Let's talk about weather.
但天气... 我们来谈谈天气吧
We know that it did postpone our Starlink launch earlier today
今天早些时候的星链发射确实因天气原因推迟了
and it does have a real chance of doing that again for this mission.
对于这次任务 依然面临着天气的严重威胁
There are a lot of storm cells being generated in central Florida
佛罗里达州中部产生了很多风暴单元
and they're heading east towards the Cape.
它们正向东朝卡角方向前进
We're still monitoring that situation and we probably will down to the last minute
我们仍在监测这一情况 也许倒计时结束的时候才有结果
but barring weather, all systems continue to be go for a lift off at 7:18 pm eastern time.
但如果不考虑天气因素 所有系统都允许在美国东部时间19:18升空
Tonight's launch is of the SAOCOM 1B satellite for our customer CONAE,
今晚发射的是CONAE的SAOCOM 1B卫星
(一级)发动机预冷
the Government of Argentina's National Civilian Space Agency.
CONAE即阿根廷政府所属的国家民用航天局
SAOCOM 1B is part of a two-satellite-system
SAOCOM 1B是双卫星系统中的一部分
that would use a radar technology known as synthetic aperture radar or SAR to monitor the Earth.
它将使用一种称为合成孔径雷达或SAR的雷达技术来监测地球
As we mentioned earlier in the webcast, SpaceX launched the first of these satellites,
正如早些时候在网络直播中说的那样 SpaceX发射了第一颗此类卫星
SAOCOM 1A in the fall of 2018.
也就是在2018年秋季发射的SAOCOM 1A
With the launch coming up in just about T-minus 6 minutes and 30 seconds.
距离发射还有6分30秒
Let's take a closer look at the capabilities of the SAOCOM 1B satellite.
让我们来仔细了解一下SAOCOM 1B卫星的功能
[Music]
[音乐]
地球观测卫星
CONAE开发的雷达任务
阿根廷开发的第一颗L波段卫星
搭载合成孔径雷达设备
重3吨
高4.7m
卫星平台直径1.2米
太阳能板13平方米
合成孔径雷达展开面积35平方米
合成孔径雷达面板7片
集成SIASGE星座卫星系统
(SIASGE即前面所提意大利与阿根廷合作星座)
目标：为阿根廷农业提供信息
目标：处理自然与人为应急情况
任务控制中心
泰费洛·塔巴內拉太空中心
科尔多瓦省Falda del Carmen
阿根廷(拥有)的地面站
火地岛
可用的地面站
肯尼亚马林迪
意大利马泰拉
挪威斯瓦尔巴
支持的地面站
美国洛杉矶
秘鲁利马
南极TrollSat
印度洋凯尔盖朗
SAOCOM任务应用
生成土壤水分地图
灌溉和施肥的决策支持
服务塔架分离
SAOCOM任务应用
洪泛区探测
水体溢油探测
SAOCOM任务应用
塌方监测
科技公司和科研机构一起为国家航天计划而努力
SAOCOM任务
发展阿根廷航天业
All right we're currently less than four minutes from liftoff.
好了 现在我们距离发射不到4分钟了
Falcon 9 is now moving into the final stages of the countdown.
猎鹰9号现在进入了倒计时的最后阶段
The vehicle remains in good health but the weather is actually now go.
火箭仍然保持良好状态 但实际上现在的天气状况也是允许的
The status has changed last minute.
天气状态已经在最后一分钟发生了变化
In terms of fuel, the first and second stages are now fully fueled with RP-1.
在燃料方面 一级和二级现在已经加满了RP-1的燃料
Launch Director received a brief that the range, weather officer is go for launch.
发射主管收到指令 负责发射区域以及天气预报的官员允许发射
LOX loading will continue for the next few minutes
在接下来的几分钟里 LOX的加注将继续进行
And also one thing you'll hear one minute before liftoff
还有一件事 你会在起飞前一分钟听到的
you'll hear the announcement that Falcon 9 is in startup mode.
也就是猎鹰9号进入启动模式的通知
This means that the rockets own internal computers are now autonomously controlling the launch countdown.
这意味着火箭内部的计算机正在自主控制发射倒计时
The SAOCOM 1B payload continues to be healthy.
SAOCOM 1B有效载荷状态良好
The Falcon 9 team is tracking no issues on the rocket.
猎鹰9号团队没发现火箭有问题
Weather has just recently opened up and is looking good
刚刚天气状态也转好了
and the range is green for launch.
同时发射区域也是绿灯放行的状态
Poll go ??? verification.
As a reminder if we don't launch today,
提醒大家 如果今天不发射
we do have that backup opportunity tomorrow pending range acceptance at 7:19 pm eastern local time.
如果发射区域条件允许的话 我们明天美国东部时间19:19有一个后备的机会
And with just under three minutes to go before launch.
还有不到三分钟就要发射了
Let's listen into the final countdown prior to liftoff.
让我们来听听起飞前的最后倒计时
All right our nine Merlin engines on the first stage are chilled.
好了 一级的九台梅林发动机都已经冷却
They're ready for flight.
它们已经为发射准备好了
The LOX loading will complete on that second stage in just a few seconds.
二级的LOX加注将在几秒钟内完成
Once that occurs you'll start seeing more of this white clouds venting.
一旦完成 你会看到更多的白云喷出
Stage 2 LOX closeout.
二级LOX停止加注
As our LOX is fully loaded uh and it's topped off,
在LOX保持在装满状态 并且不断蒸发的时候
you'll start seeing this condensation. These clouds form more and more right up until liftoff.
你会看到这种凝结的云层 越来越多 直到升空
启动
猎鹰9号的飞控
接管了倒计时
Falcon 9 is in startup.
猎鹰9号已进入启动状态
All right we have entered startup mode.
好了 我们已经进入启动模式
Falcon 9 has taken over the remainder of the countdown.
猎鹰9号已经接管了剩余的倒计时时间
We're just waiting for the go-for-launch callouts.
我们正在等待发射前的呼号
Stage two pressed for flight.
二级(储罐)加压至飞行压力
LD go for launch.
发射主管允许发射
T-minus 30 seconds.
倒计时30秒
T-minus 15 seconds.
倒计时15秒
Falcon 9 is configured for flight.
猎鹰9号完成发射配置
10 9 8 7 6 5 4 3 2 1 0
速度          高度
二级遥测数据
Ignition
点火
起飞
猎鹰9号的固定夹具释放
飞行过程开始
and lift off the Falcon's first East Coast polar launch over Argentina.
猎鹰首次东海岸极轨发射起飞 将飞越阿根廷
Vehicle is pitching downrange.
猎鹰9号程序转弯
Stage 1 propulsion is nominal.
一级火箭推力正常
We're now 40 seconds in the flight.
现在是发射后40秒
Falcon 9 has taken off.
猎鹰9号已经起飞
It's cleared the tower.
它离开了发射塔
And we're currently throttling down to prepare for Maximum Q
猎鹰9号的发动机现正节流 准备进入MAX-Q状态
Power and telemetry nominal.
动力 遥测信号正常
that's the point of maximum aerodynamic pressure.
MAX-Q是指最大气动压力
It's at 1 minute and 12 seconds.
这发生在发射后1分12秒
Vehicle is supersonic.
火箭超音速
Vehicle has reached maximum aerodynamic pressure.
火箭已达到最大气动力压力
Max-Q
最大气动压力 - 这是火箭
(在上升段)受到的最大气动压力
You've heard it.
你听到了
We've reached MAX-Q.
我们已经达到了MAX-Q
At this point the loads in the vehicle become less and less
在此时 火箭的(气动)负荷越来越小
as the atmosphere gets thinner.
随着大气层的变薄
We're now able to throttle those Merlin engines back up
梅林发动机的油门现在可以加回来了
Vehicle is clear and OK.(?)
at its maximum power like right now.
现在调整至最大功率
M-Vac engine chill started.
真空梅林发动机预冷开始
The vehicle consumes more than 700 gallons of fuel per second.
现在 火箭每秒消耗2.64m³燃料
All is looking good with our first stage is trajectory.
一级火箭的轨道正常
The next couple of events...
接下来会发生几件事
There are five events one after another.
会一连串发生5件事
First our main engine cuts off on our first stage.
首先是 一级火箭发动机关机
The stages will separate.
一二级分离
Our first stage will then flip around to begin its landing attempt.
一级火箭会翻转 并开始尝试着陆
The second stage's Merlin Vacuum Engine will ignite for a Second Engine Start One.
二级的梅林真空发动机将点火 也就是二级发动机第一次点火
The first stages Boost Back Burn will start.
而一级火箭的返场点火将开始
It's one of three burns to help us land.
这是准备着陆的三次点火之一
They occur one after another in about 15 seconds.
它们会在15秒内相继发生
And this is that first polar orbit.
这会是首次(东海岸)极轨发射
You can see through the clouds here.
你可以透过云层看到下方的景色
You'll see some unique views you haven't seen from Falcon 9 over Florida.
这景色会和平时从佛罗里达发射的不太一样
MECO
一级发动机关机
And we have MECO.
分级
一级从二级上分离
Stage Separation confirmed.
一二级分离确认
SES-1
二级发动机
第一次点火
M-Vac ignition.
梅林真空发动机点火
一级火箭返场
一级火箭开始进行返回地球的
三次点火序列中的第一次
All right all of those events happen successfully one after another.
好了 所有这些事件都相继成功地发生了
This Boost Back Burn, it'll last about 40 seconds.
这次助推返场点火 将持续大概40秒
Stage 1 Boost Back startup.
一级火箭返场点火开始
As you see on the left hand side of the screen.
屏幕的左边就是助推的画面
On the right hand side you will see our second stage carrying those three satellites to orbit.
右手边则是二级火箭 它会将这三颗卫星送入轨道
And coming up next in about 20 seconds that Boost Back Burn will end and then we'll have our fairing deployment.
接下来大约20秒后 助推器的返场点火将结束 然后是抛整流罩
Stage one Boost Back shutdown.
一级火箭返场点火结束
All right one of those first landing burn, the Boost Back Burns uh has successfully ended.
好了 准备着陆的第一次点火 返场点火结束了
Our two fairing halves will now jettison to expose the satellites to space.
两瓣儿整流罩将分离 这样就把卫星暴露在太空中
You see the first stage has already been turned around
你看 一级已经翻转过来了
and you can see the Nitrogen from our attitude control system helping guide it back.
你可以看到姿态控制系统喷出氮气 来调整火箭姿态
抛整流罩
火箭顶部的保护性鼻锥
被抛离
Fairing Separation confirmed.
整流罩分离确认
There you see our two fairing halves are jettisoned.
现在你可以看到我们的两瓣儿整流罩被抛离
Acquisition signal Bermuda.
百慕大遥测信号正常
You can even see them in the background there on our M-Vac engine.
你甚至可以在拍摄真空梅林发动机的镜头背景中看到它们
And you can see them from land too.
还有在陆地上的机位
It'll take us some time to get those uh to come back down.
等整流罩飘下来需要一定时间
We'll keep you posted on the update.
我们会随时向你们汇报最新情况的
We are T-plus 4 minutes and 13 seconds into flight.
现在是发射后4分13秒
Everything is looking great for tonight's mission.
今晚的任务一切都很顺利
On the right hand side of your screen is a view of our second stage specifically its Merlin Vacuum Engine.
在你屏幕的右边是二级梅林真空发动机的画面
We also call it M-Vac engine for short.
简称M-Vac
实际上在任务完成后，二级火箭还进行了降轨点火，并很快离轨再入，
这也是为什么在北美防空司令部的两行根数数据中找不到这个二级，消息来源
forum.nasaspaceflight.com/index.php?topic=47380.msg2126772#msg2126772
It's currently in the first and only planned M-Vac burn.
它目前正在进行第一次也是唯一一次计划中的点火
The first burn should last for about another four minutes.
这次点火应该会再持续四分钟左右
On the left hand side of your screen is a view of our first stage looking downward.
在你屏幕的左侧是一级火箭向下看的画面
It's continuing to fall back towards Earth.
它正持续向地球坠落
The next milestone for the first stage is its first stage Entry Burn.
一级火箭的下一个里程碑事件是再入点火
Falcon 9 needs to execute an Entry Burn to slow itself down before hitting the dense parts of the atmosphere.
猎鹰9号需要在进入大气层的浓厚区域之前 执行一次再入点火来减缓自己的速度
Without this second burn,
如果没有这第二次点火
relying on the atmosphere alone to slow Falcon 9 down would put unnecessary strain on the rocket.
仅仅依靠大气层来减慢速度 会给猎鹰9号带来不必要的压力
That Entry Burn is coming up at T-plus six minutes and 10 seconds.
那个再入点火发生在发射后6分10秒
Second stage is following the nominal trajectory.
二级轨道正常
Acquisition of signal South Texas.
南德克萨斯遥测信号正常
You may have also noticed that we've deployed our four hypersonic grid fins.
你们可能也注意到了 一级火箭已经展开了四个高超音速栅格翼
Those are the honeycomb like structures that you see on the left hand side of your screen.
就是你在屏幕左侧看到的蜂窝状结构
They help to guide the first stage back during descent by moving the center of pressure on the vehicle.
它们通过移动火箭上的压力中心 来让一级火箭返回地球
Again those bursts of gas are Nitrogen.
同样 这些突然出现的气体是氮气
It's absolutely normal.
这是肯定是正常的
And those help to orient the rocket during its descent back towards Earth.
这些气体用于调整火箭姿态 让其返回地球
And we're about 20 seconds away from our second burn.
我们离第二次(为着陆准备的)点火还有大约20秒的时间
The Entry Burn.
也就是再入点火
Stage 2 FTS has (been) safed.
二级飞行中止系统关闭
一级火箭再入
一级火箭开始它的再入点火
减速进入大气层
Stage one Entry Burn startup.
一级再入点火开始
And three Merlin engines have relit.
三台梅林发动机已经重新点火
And are currently slowing the first stage down before it hits those dense parts of the atmosphere.
目前正在减缓一级的速度 在它进入大气层的浓厚部分之前
Second stage on the right hand side of the screen is continuing to perform as expected.
屏幕右侧的二级继续按照预期飞行
Stage one Entry Burn shutdown.
一级再入点火结束
And that is our second burn completed.
这样 第二次点火就完成了
As we mentioned earlier we are going to be attempting to recover this booster back at land on landing zone one.
正如我们之前提到的 我们将尝试在陆地上的第一着陆区回收这个助推器
The first stage has one more burn left that is the landing burn.
一级还剩下一次点火 那就是着陆点火
Stage 1 FTS has (been) safed.
一级飞行中止系统关闭
It begins just before we touch down and provides the booster a soft descent before we land.
它会发生在火箭触地之前不久 让助推器进行软着陆
Second stage's still following nominal trajectory.
二级轨道正常
During this period, the landing legs will also be deploying.
在此期间 着陆腿也将展开
You might be able to catch it right before we touch down.
你大概会在着陆前瞬间看到它的展开
They're stowed at the base of the vehicle and made up of state-of-the-art carbon fiber and aluminum honeycomb.
它们被收纳在火箭的底部 由最先进的碳纤维和蜂窝铝组成
Stage one transonic.
一级火箭速度减至亚音速
You see the Cape getting closer and closer.
你可以看到一级火箭离卡角越来越近了
Now what a cool view.
多么壮丽的景色
一级火箭着陆
一级火箭开始它的着陆点火
减速并于LZ-1陆上着陆场着陆
the first stage is passing through the cloud layers right now.
一级火箭现正通过云层
Stage one Landing Burn startup.
一级着陆点火开始
And here comes Falcon 9 attempting its fourth landing.
(这枚)猎鹰9号正在尝试第四次着陆
Stage one landing leg deploy.
一级火箭着陆腿展开
And you could not ask for a better landing than that.
真是完美的着陆
Stage 1 landing confirmed.
一级火箭着陆成功
Falcon 9 has landed once again.
猎鹰9号又一次着陆了
That is number four for this first stage booster
这是这枚助推器的第四次着陆
and the 58th overall of an orbital class rocket.
也是轨道级火箭的第58次着陆
What a way to start off tonight's mission.
今晚任务的开场方式针不戳
The second stage and our primary mission are still continuing and remain healthy.
二级火箭和主要任务仍在继续进行并且状态良好
The next milestone for the second stage is Second Engine Cutoff One,
二级火箭的下一个里程碑事件是二级发动机第一次关机
also known as SECO-1.
也被称为SECO-1
And that is coming up at T-plus 10 minutes and five seconds.
这会发生在发射后10分5秒位置
During SECO-1 we'll be shutting down the second stage's M-Vac engine.
SECO-1时 二级的M-Vac会关机
And as we approach this period we'll be listening very closely for two call outs.
在接近这段时间时 注意听两个呼号
Verification of SECO-1 and then confirmation of a good orbital insertion.
SECO-1确认和轨道注入正常
Both are going to be critical to ensuring that we deliver all three payloads to their intended orbits tonight.
这两点将确认三个有效载荷被送入预定轨道
And we're waiting for that period.
那么我们就等待这段时间到来吧
Some fun facts.
一些有趣的事实
The engine you see on screen can produce over 200000 pounds of thrust.
你在屏幕上看到的发动机可以产生超过90.7吨的推力
The second stage is currently traveling at over 20000 kilometers an hour.
二级火箭目前以5555km/s的速度飞行
Start of terminal guidance
开始末端制导
At those speeds you could travel from Los Angeles to New York in just 12 minutes.
以这种速度 从洛杉矶到纽约只需12分钟
Very very fast.
非常非常快
We're about 20 seconds away from SECO-1.
我们距离SECO -1还有20秒的时间
SECO-1
二级发动机第一次关机
And we have SECO.
SECO确认
And the second stage Merlin Vacuum Engine has successfully had SECO-1.
那么二级真空梅林发动机成功完成了SECO-1
Nominal orbit insertion.
轨道注入正常
And that is the other callout we were waiting to hear on a good orbital insertion.
这也是我们等待的另一个呼号 即良好的轨道注入
In just about three minutes we will have the first of our three deployments.
再过三分钟 我们将进行三次部署中的第一次
Until then we are going to take a short break
在那之前 我们将进行短暂的休息
and be back around the T-plus 13-minute mark for the deployment of the SAOCOM 1B satellite.
并在发射后13分钟左右回来 那时会部署SAOCOM 1B卫星
Loss of signal Bermuda as expected.
预期中的百慕大遥测信号丢失
[Music]
[音乐]
Acquisition signal Peru.
秘鲁遥测信号正常
[Music]
[音乐]
Well welcome back from our mini coast phase.
好了 欢迎从这个迷你的滑行阶段回来
For those of you just joining us
对于那些刚刚才观看网络直播的人 简单介绍下
we successfully have launched our Falcon 9 rocket from Cape Canaveral on a polar orbit trajectory.
我们成功地从卡纳维拉尔角发射了猎鹰9号火箭到极轨道上
We had a successful stage separation,
一二级分离成功
a successful land landing, the fourth landing for this booster
成功着陆 也是该助推器的第四次着陆
and we're waiting the deployment of the SAOCOM 1B satellite.
而现在我们正等待SAOCOM 1B卫星的部署
It's just about 10 seconds 15 seconds away.
还有15秒左右就到了
It's the second and final satellite in this constellation.
它是这个星座的第二颗也是最后一颗卫星
We first launched its sister satellite SAOCOM 1A in the fall of 2018.
我们在2018年秋天首次发射了它的姐妹卫星SAOCOM 1A
SAOCOM separation confirmed.
SAOCOM分离确认
All right you've seen it.
好了 你已经看到了
We heard it.
我们听到了
Successful deployment of that SAOCOM 1B satellite.
成功部署了那颗SAOCOM 1B卫星
And as a reminder this satellite and SAOCOM 1A satellite's goal is to gather soil moisture.
并提醒大家 这颗卫星和SAOCOM 1A卫星的目标是收集土壤水分
It helps increase the productivity and competitiveness of the agriculture sector.
它有助于提高农业部门的生产力和竞争力
It helps us generate risk maps that can help control crop disease.
它可以帮助我们生成风险图 帮助控制农作物疾病
It helps implement better fertilizer systems and provide early flood warnings.
它有助于实施更好的施肥系统 并提供早期洪水警报
These two SAOCOM satellites work together with Italy's COSMO-SkyMed constellation
这两颗SAOCOM卫星与意大利的COSMO-SkyMed星座一起工作
and they work together by providing up to 225 Earth images per day.
它们每天提供多达225张地球图像
But we still do have two satellites left to deploy.
但我们还有两颗卫星需要部署
we're going to go into another coast phase.
我们将进入另一个滑行阶段
This one will last about 45 minutes.
这个阶段将持续约45分钟
We're going to take a break
我们要休息一下
but we're leaving you with an animation that shows where we are in that coast phase
但我们会给你们留下一个动画 显示我们在滑行阶段中的位置
We'll be back at about T-plus one hour for the deployment of the Tyvak-0172 and GNOMES-1 Rideshare satellites.
我们将在发射后1小时回来部署Tyvak-0172和GNOMES-1这两个拼车卫星
We'll see you then.
我们到时见
[Music]
[音乐]
Argentina(?) spacecraft team reports good solar array deployed.
阿根廷航天器团队报告太阳能面板展开正常
[Music]
[音乐]
Loss of Signal Peru as expected.
预期中的秘鲁遥测信号丢失
[Music]
[音乐]
Acquisition signal Reef(?).
Welcome back to the webcast of the SAOCOM 1B mission.
欢迎回到SAOCOM 1B任务的网络直播
If you're just joining us, we're wrapping up our coast phase
如果你刚刚才观看网络直播 滑行阶段刚刚结束
and close to the end of today's mission which launched this evening at 7:18 pm eastern.
并接近今天东部时间19:18进行的任务的尾声
We then had successful lighting and shutdown of our second stage Merlin Vacuum Engine.
我们之前成功地进行了二级梅林真空发动机的点火和关机
Then a successful deployment of the SAOCOM 1B satellite for Argentina's national space program.
然后成功部署了阿根廷国家航天计划的SAOCOM 1B卫星
Coming up we have the deployment of our two rideshare satellites.
接下来我们将部署两颗拼车卫星
First up is the GNOMES-1 satellite for PlanetIQ that occurs at T-plus one hour one minute and 37 seconds.
首先是为PlanetIQ公司部署的GNOMES-1号卫星 在发射后1小时1分37秒时发生
Followed shortly after by the Tyvak-0172 satellite.
紧接着是Tyvak-0172卫星
For the GNOMES-1 satellite, due to the placement of our cameras,
对于GNOMES-1号卫星 由于我们的摄像头位置
it's not likely that we'll have visual confirmation of the GNOMES-1 deployment.
我们不可能通过画面确认GNOMES-1的部署情况
So we'll be listening in on the communication channels for that.
所以我们会通过(任务控制的)通信频道来收听
And a little bit more about PlanetIQ,
而关于PlanetIQ的更多信息
they design build launch and operate
他们设计 建造 发射和运营
one of the most advanced constellation of radio occultation weather forecasting satellites.
最先进的无线电掩星气象预报卫星星座之一
Radio occultation is a technology that measures and analyzes the signals generated by GPS satellites
无线电掩星是一种测量和分析GPS卫星产生的信号的技术
to determine weather data such as pressure, temperature and water vapor.
通过这种技术 以确定气压 温度和水汽等天气数据
This data is used in weather forecast models to greatly improve the accuracy
这些数据被用于天气预报模型中 大大提高了天气预报的准确性
and extend the range of weather predictions.
并扩大天气预报的范围
And here's a fun fact about PlanetIQ's micro satellite.
关于PlanetIQ的微型卫星 有一个有趣的事实
It's about the size of a carry-on bag weighing about 39 kilograms or 86 pounds.
它的大小和一个手提包差不多 重约39公斤或86磅
We're a few seconds out from the GNOMES-1 payload deploy.
距离GNOMES-1的有效载荷部署还有几秒钟的时间
PlanetIQ separation confirmed.
PlanetIQ分离确认
And we did get confirmation that the GNOMES-1 satellite did successfully separate.
我们确认GNOMES-1号卫星成功分离了
We're now waiting on our final deployment today and that is of the Tyvak-0172 satellite.
我们现在正在等待今天的最后一次部署 那是Tyvak-0172卫星的部署
And for this one we should be able to see the deployment.
对于这颗卫星 我们应该可以看到部署情况
We're just about 15 to 20 seconds out.
大概还要15到20秒的时间
Tyvak separation confirmed.
Tyvak分离确认
And we did get confirmation of the Tyvak-0172 satellite separation.
我们确认Tyvak-0172卫星分离了
That is our last payload for tonight.
这是今晚最后一个有效载荷
It's been an exciting evening.
这是一个激动人心的夜晚
We saw a successful liftoff from our Cape Canaveral Air Force Station launch pad at 7:18 pm eastern,
美国东部时间19:18从卡纳维拉尔角空军基地发射台成功升空
the first polar orbit launch for SpaceX at the Cape
SpaceX在卡角的首次极地轨道发射
and the first originating from Florida in decades.
同样也是几十年来第一个源自佛罗里达州的极轨道发射
From there a successful stage separation,
在那之后 经历了成功的一二级分离
a land landing of our first stage back at landing zone 1 which marks
我们的一级火箭在1号着陆区着陆 这标志着
and this is a small correction the 59th landing of an orbital of an orbital class rocket
当然这是一个小小的纠正 这是第59次轨道级火箭着陆
not the 58th.
而不是第58次
And finally the deployment of the SAOCOM 1B satellite for the Argentinian Space Agency
最后 为阿根廷航天局部署了SAOCOM 1B卫星
along with our two rideshare customers.
以及我们的两个拼车客户
With that said we will be bringing our webcast to an end.
说到这里 我们的网络直播将进入尾声
But before we go we'd like to thank our customer CONAE for tonight's mission
但在我们离开之前 我们要感谢我们的客户CONAE 拼车客户PlanetIQ
and their great support as well as rideshare customer PlanetIQ.
对我们任务的大力支持
We'd also like to thank the United States Air Force for range support
我们还要感谢美国空军的发射区域支持
as well as the Federal Aviation Administration for the licensing of today's mission.
以及美国联邦航空管理局对今天任务的许可
Please continue to follow us on SpaceX.com for future missions and milestones
as well as our twitter and instagram profiles.
And if you're as excited by what you've seen tonight as we are
and you want to join our team
please visit SpaceX.com careers to learn more about working with us at SpaceX.
And finally thank you to you all of our viewers for your support and for tuning in.
最后感谢各位观众对我们的支持和收看
We hope you have a great night.
祝你今晚过得愉快
[Music]
[音乐]